### **Michalis Anastasiou**

Role: Software Developer Phone number: (+357) 96605928 (Mobile) | Email address michanastasiou9@qmail.com

#### **About me**

Highly skilled software development professional bringing solid experience in software design, development and integration. Offering advanced knowledge of in-demand programming languages. Experienced in Java and Golang. Background writing code and developing systems for telecom and fintech applications.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# 01/01/2024 – Current Limassol Full Stack (FINOVEX)

- Implementing API's written in Golang.
- o Adding frontend components written in React.
- o Part of scrum team using sprints and agile methodologies
- o Automating procedures needed from financial department.

## 01/07/2022 – 01/01/2024 Limassol Software Developer (AMDOCS)

- o Mainly working in the database using SQL developer.
- o Extracted and interpreted data patterns to translate findings into actionable outcomes.
- o Speaking with the customer in order to identify the root cause of errors and misalignments in the data.
- o Using Power BI dashboards in order to analyze and categorize data issues. Performing data analysis.
- o Using agile methodologies (Scrum teams).
- Created various Excel documents to assist with pulling metrics data and presenting information to stakeholders for concise explanations of best placement for needed resources.
- Created scripts with PL/SQL in order to automate some procedures.
- Completed data cleaning and data validation of existing spreadsheets to promote robust data management platform, resulting in accurate data analysis and entry.
- o Fixing code bugs written in Java.
- o Rewarded for effectiveness in short span of time, outstanding performance and can-do approach toward team tasks.

# 01/06/2021 – 01/07/2021 Nicosia, Cyprus Information Technology Trainee (NET MASTERS)

- o Created servers (Linux) and databases for big companies in Cyprus.
- Other responsibilities of the company are backup of the data, maintenance and IT service for the employees.

#### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/10/2017 – 01/08/2023 Grade: 7.65

Integrated Master's Degree (MEng) Technical University of Crete

- High quality theoretical and hands-on education of 5 years, exploring modern technology subjects such as electronics, control systems, computer science, telecommunications and data science.
- Thesis: Finding Correlated Attributes in Data Sets Using Apache Flink. Used Apache Kafka for source, sink and Apache Flink for data processing. Live processing on data from different sources in order to find similarities using Pearson Correlation and Ranking Techniques.

Address Crete, Greece

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

### **PROJECTS**

SQL Database, AD Blocker (Bash Shell), Hotel Board Game (Unity 3D, C#), Build dashboards (Power BI), Build Dashboards (Looker, Look ML) Gained basic experience on using Looker and Look ML, Python (NumPy, Pandas). Currently learning JavaScript.

https://github.com/Michalis98

### **SKILLS / LANGUAGES**

Skills: Basic knowledge on Looker & Look ML, Power BI, Java, Excel, Data Analysis, Agile Mythologies (Scrum Team), Good SQL knowledge (Postgre SQL and SQL Developer), GitHub, DevOps Certification

Soft Skills: Teamwork, Discipline, Communication and Interpersonal skills, Working Experience in online gaming, Self-motivated, Able to work on own initiative

Languages: English (English GSCE), Greek (Native)